adelaidemetro.com.au 2016-12-14

# Adelaide Metro - Terms and Conditions

## Copyright 

The Government of South Australia supports and encourages the dissemination and exchange of public sector information, and endorses the use of the [Australian Governments Open Access and Licensing Framework](http://www.ausgoal.gov.au/ "Go to the Ausgoal website") by its agencies. 

  With the exception of the Piping Shrike emblem, images, and other material or devices protected by a trademark and subject to review by the Government of South Australia at all times, the content of this website is licensed under the [Creative Commons Australia Attribution 3.0 Licence](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/au/deed.en "Go to the Creative Commons Website"). The Government of South Australia requests attribution as ’Adelaide Metro’. All other rights are reserved.

 The Government of South Australia has undertaken reasonable enquiries to identify material owned by third parties and secure permission for its reproduction. Permission may need to be obtained from third parties to reuse their material. 

#### Enquiries

Use the contact form to make an enquiry about the use of Government of South Australia material. 

## Disclaimer 

Use of the information and data contained within this site or these pages is at your sole risk. 

If you rely on the information on this site you are responsible for ensuring by independent verification its accuracy, currency or completeness. 

This site includes links to other websites operated by community, business and government. These linked websites will have their own terms and conditions of use and you should familiarise yourself with these. 

All linked websites are linked 'as is' and the Government of South Australia: 

  * does not sponsor, endorse or necessarily approve of any material on websites linked from or to this Site;
  * does not make any warranties or representations regarding the quality, accuracy, merchantability or fitness for purpose of any material on websites linked from or to this Site;
  * does not make any warranties or representations that material on other websites to which this site is linked does not infringe the intellectual property rights of any person anywhere in the world; and
  * does not authorise the infringement of any intellectual property rights contained in material in other websites by linking this site to those other websites.

If you use automatic language translation services in connection with this site you do so at your own risk. 

The information and data on this site is subject to change without notice. The Government of South Australia may revise this disclaimer at any time by updating this posting. 

The Government of South Australia, its agents, instrumentalities, officers and employees: 

  * make no representations, express or implied, as to the accuracy of the information and data contained on this site
  * make no representations, express or implied, as to the accuracy or usefulness of any translation of the information on this site or any linked website into another language
  * make no representations as to the availability of the site and the availability of websites linked from or to the site
  * accept no liability however arising for any loss resulting from the use of the site and any information and data or reliance placed on it (including translated information and data)
  * make no representations, either expressed or implied, as to the suitability of the said information and data for any particular purpose
  * accepts no liability for any interference with or damage to a user's computer, software or data occurring in connection with or relating to this Site or its use or any website linked to this site
  * do not represent or warrant that applications or payments initiated through this site will in fact be received or made to the intended recipient. Users are advised to confirm the application or payment by other means. 

## Privacy and Security 

The Department of Planning, Transport and Infrastructure and Adelaide Metro respect your privacy. 

This privacy statement tells you what information we collect and how that information is stored and used. 

#### Data automatically collected _ _ __

Whenever you visit our web site, our internet service providers (ISP’s) automatically record: 

  * your IP address
  * the date and time of your visit
  * the pages you access
  * the documents you download
  * the type of browser
  * the operating system and type of device you use.

This information does not identify you personally. No attempt is made to identify you except, in the unlikely event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise a warrant to inspect our service provider's logs. 

Periodically we use independent measurement and research companies to gather non-personal information regarding the visitors to our website on our behalf using cookies, log file data and code which is embedded on our website. 

These statistics tell us how our site is being used and helps us improve it to make your visit useful, informative and enjoyable. 

We also collect the key words you use when you do a search of our site. This information is not linked to any other data we collect. We use this information to find out what people are looking for and how we can improve our services. 

#### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of data that a web site can transfer to your computer hard drive for record keeping. Adelaide Metro may use cookies to help you access and use our site and improve the service we offer. There is no attempt to identify you personally. 

The use of cookies in this way is widespread and commonly accepted by the Internet community. You can set your browser to reject a cookie that we attempt to place on your computer. However you may then be limited in your use of some areas of the site. 

### Personal information you submit

Adelaide Metro will record your name, email address and phone number if you send us a message or you include it in an online form. It will only be used to send you a reply and not added to a mailing list or used for any other purpose without your consent. 

Your name, email address and phone number is stored in a secure area and only forwarded to appropriate staff so they can answer your question. 

### My Metro

#### Registration

My Metro allows you to save your favourite timetables, trips, stops and receive SMS or email alerts when these services change. 

Adelaide Metro will record your email address and your mobile phone number and any travel information you submit when you register for “My Metro”. This information will only be used for the purpose of notifying you of public transport service changes. 

When you choose to receive special offers, promotions and new development information we will use your mobile phone number or email address for the purpose of notifying you of these offers. You can un-subscribe or  change your preferences at any time from your account. 

Adelaide Metro may use this information to conduct research and in the improvement of service to customers. Information you provide may be disclosed to our service providers to provide you with the information you have requested but will not be disclosed for any other purpose without your consent. 

## Privacy and metrocard 

### Registered metrocards

#### Registration

Registration of your metrocard requires that some personal information is held by us (The Department for Planning, Transport and Infrastructure).   
If you register a metrocard, the Adelaide Fare Collection System securely stores your personal information. 

This personal information is necessary for the purpose of verifying your identity. This enables us to communicate with you and provide you with access to the full range of metrocard services. 

When you register you can choose to receive information from Adelaide Metro. When you choose to receive special offers, promotions and new development information we will use your Customer Records for the purpose of notifying you of these offers. You can un-subscribe or change your preferences at any time from your account. 

Adelaide Metro may use this information to conduct research and in the improvement of service to customers. Information you provide may be disclosed to our service providers to provide you with the information you have requested but will not be disclosed for any other purpose without your consent. 

#### When you validate

When you validate your metrocard we record the stop, vehicle number, date and time, the service number and fare deducted for the trip. 

We update our relevant databases and store the validation activity for auditing purposes. This information is associated with your customer record, so we can provide you with a record of your travel history. 

**Registered Metrocards**

**Customer Records** |    |  **Metrocard Services Available**   |  ** **  
---|---|---|---  
Name  |  Yes  |  Recharge Online  |   Yes  |    |     
Address  |  Yes  |  Auto Recharge  |   Yes  |    |     
Date of Birth  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Agent Recharge  |   Yes  |    |     
Phone Number  |  Yes  |  Ticket Machine Recharge  |   Yes  |    |     
Email Address  |  Yes  |  Online Metrocard Management  |   Yes  |    |     
Metrocard Number  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Protection  |   Yes  |    |     
  
### Unregistered Metrocards

You can choose to use your metrocard anonymously, by not registering your metrocard.  
If you choose this option no personal information is held by us.   
This also means we cannot provide you access to the full range of metrocard services. 

#### When you validate an unregistered metrocard

When you validate your metrocard we anonymously record the stop, vehicle number, date and time, the service number and fare deducted for the trip. No personally identifiable information is recorded by us. 

We update our relevant databases and store the anonymous validation activity for auditing purposes. 

**Unregistered Metrocards**

**Customer Records** |    |  **Metrocard Services Available** |  ** **  
---|---|---|---  
Name  |  No  |  Recharge Online  |   No   
Address  |  No  |  Auto Recharge  |   No   
Date of Birth  |  No  |  Metrocard Agent Recharge  |   Yes   
Phone Number  |  No  |  Ticket Machine Recharge  |   Yes   
Email Address  |  No  |  Online Metrocard Management  |   No   
Metrocard Number  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Protection  |   No   
  
### Seniors Cards 

The Seniors Card is issued by the Seniors Card Unit of the Office for the Ageing and entitles card holders to discounts, and benefits from businesses around the state. Your South Australian Seniors Card also serves as a Seniors metrocard, providing card holder’s public transport fare concessions. 

You can choose to provide consent for personal information held by the Seniors Card Unit to be provided to us (The Department for Planning Transport and Infrastructure). This personal information enables us to provide you with a Seniors Card metrocard and access to the full range of metrocard services, online, in person and over the phone. 

You can contact the Seniors Card Unit to learn more about your options at [www.sa.gov.au/seniorscard](http://www.sa.gov.au/seniorscard "Go to the Seniors Card Website"), email seniorscard@sa.gov.au or phone 1800 819 961 (free call). 

When you choose this option and register your Seniors Card metrocard, the Adelaide Fare Collection System will securely store your personal information. 

#### When you validate

When you validate your Seniors Card metrocard we record the stop, vehicle number, date and time, the service number and fare deducted for the trip. 

We update our relevant databases and store the validation activity for auditing purposes. This information is associated with your customer record so we can provide you with a record of your travel history and access to the full range of Metrocard Services. 

**Registered Seniors Card Metrocard**

**Customer Records** |    |  **Metrocard Services Available** |     
---|---|---|---  
Name  |  Yes  |  Recharge online  |  Yes   
Address  |  Yes  |  Auto Rechange  |  Yes   
Date of Birth  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Agent Recharge  |  Yes   
Phone Number  |  Yes  |  Ticket Machine Management  |  Yes   
Email Address  |  Optional, required   
for online Metrocard management  |  Online Metrocard Management  |  Yes   
Metrocard Number  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Protection  |  Yes   
Senior Card Number  |  Yes  |    |     
  
### Anonymised Seniors Cards

The Seniors Card is issued by the Seniors Card Unit of the Office for the Ageing.  
At any time you can choose not to consent to personal information held by the Seniors Card Unit to be provided to us (The Department for Planning Transport and Infrastructure). 

If you do not provide consent or wish to change your consent, you must contact the Seniors Card Unit [www.sa.gov.au/seniorscard](http://www.sa.gov.au/seniorscard "Go to the Seniors Card Website"), email seniorscard@sa.gov.au or phone 1800 819 961 (free call). 

If you choose this unregistered and anonymous option no personally identifiable information is recorded by us. You can use your Seniors Card as a Seniors metrocard, however we will be unable to provide you access to the full range of metrocard services available. 

#### When you validate

When you validate your unregistered Seniors Card metrocard we record the stop, vehicle number, date and time, the service number and fare deducted for the trip. No personally identifiable information is recorded by us. 

We update our relevant databases and store the anonymous validation activity for auditing purposes. 

**Unregistered Seniors Card Metrocard**

**Customer Records** |    |  **Metrocard Services Available** |     
---|---|---|---  
Name  |  No  |  Recharge online  |  No   
Address  |  No  |  Auto Recharge  |  No   
Date of Birth  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Agent Recharge  |  Yes   
Phone Number  |  No  |  Ticket Machine Recharge  |  Yes   
Email Address  |  No  |  Online Metrocard Management  |  No   
Metrocard Number  |  Yes  |  Metrocard Protection  |  Yes   
Senior Card Number  |  Yes  |    |     
  
#### Your Financial transactions

If you perform a recharge transaction we update our relevant databases and store your transaction history for audit purposes. The Adelaide Metro and the AFCS (Metrocard) websites do not store your credit card or debit card information. 

#### Payments

If you pay online, your payment is processed by Bizgate, the South Australian Government's secure e-commerce facility. All information is securely transmitted using standard encryption processes. We recommend that you check the [Privacy Statement](http://forms.bizgate.sa.gov.au/terms.htm "Go to http://forms.bizgate.sa.gov.au/terms.htm - opens in a new window") on the sa.gov.au website. 

#### Access and correction of your personal information

You can access the information we hold about you by logging into your metrocard account. You can access and update your personal information directly. You can also access and update the personal information we hold about you when you contact us via the Adelaide Metro InfoLine or at an Adelaide Metro InfoCentre. 

Access to your personal information is restricted to Adelaide Metro and the Department of Planning, Transport and Infrastructure personnel who need to transact business with you. 

If you are a parent or guardian, you may request access to the personal information of a minor. Reasonable proof of your identity is required in addition to reasonable proof of a relationship to the minor before any information is disclosed. 

You may arrange for secure third party access to your Metrocard account if required however, a third party cannot modify your account details as this could prevent you from accessing your account. 

You may also request that your partner may access your personal information on your behalf. Requests for access to personal information of a partner require consent of the partner. 

Your name, address and personal information will not be sold or given away to any other person, company or organisation without your consent. However, we must cooperate fully should a situation arise where we are required by law or legal process to provide information about a customer. 

#### Security

Adelaide Metro is committed to ensuring a high level of security for all online transactions. Online forms and transactions are secured using industry standard 128-bit [Secure Socket Layer (SSL)](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security) encryption. This minimises the possibility of information being intercepted by unauthorised parties. 

Notwithstanding the above, Adelaide Metro makes no warranty in respect of the strength or effectiveness of the above encryption and is not responsible for events arising from unauthorised access to information secured using these technologies. 

If you do not wish to transmit the required details electronically you can contact us in a variety of other ways. 

##### **Other websites**

This privacy statement covers only the Adelaide Metro web site and Adelaide Metro web based services. Our privacy policies do not apply to any other sites, even when we have provided you with a direct link. We recommend that you check the privacy statements of other web sites. 

##### **Privacy guidelines**

This site is operated in compliance with the Government of South Australia's information privacy principles (IPPs), a copy of which can be obtained on [the Department of the Premier and Cabinet website](http://dpc.sa.gov.au/premier-and-cabinet-circulars "Go to the department of premier and cabinet website").  
This privacy statement will be continually reviewed in line with the ongoing development of this Internet site. If you have any questions about our privacy policies please contact us.
